# SALAMI ABIODUN

Gbagada Lagos | +2348154224416 | Salamabiodun01@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Analytical Digital Marketing Executive with 5 years of extensive experience planning, developing, managing and implementing digital marketing strategies. Polished in measuring ROIs and KPIs, preparing and managing digital marketing budgets and overseeing company's social media accounts. Insightful Digital Marketing Executive bringing 5 years of hands-on experience managing digital marketing campaigns heavily focused on customer retention and revenue generation.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Marketing campaign management
- Customer Relationship Management
- Internet and E-mail Marketing
- Brand-building strategies
- Demand Generation Marketing
- Competitive and Trend Analysis
- Tactical planning

- Partnership Marketing
- Team management
- Product Launch
- Reliable and trustworthy
- Active listening
- Organizational skills
- Organization

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### CAESARS LUXURY HOTEL

#### DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE

2021-Present

- Oversaw social media and digital marketing strategy to increase brand exposure and audience engagement.
- Utilized Twitter and Facebook to promote products, services and content.
- Developed targeted strategies and project plans to drive vision and enhance business value.
- Designed, managed and maintained company website by writing content, directing video designs and designing email, HTML and in-text email promotions.
- Developed marketing packages involving web design, remarketing campaigns, key phrase packages and new media advertising campaigns to increase search engine optimization for clients.
- Created and implemented marketing campaigns and directory services to help clients capitalize on new media and Internet advertising opportunities.
- Interfaced with clients to discuss budget allocation to determine project scope.
- Performed competitor analysis to identify high-value keyword and backlink options.
- Hired, trained and mentored sales and marketing staff dedicated to employing Google AdWords, Google Analytics and other SEO techniques and metrics sources.
- Managed search engine accounts for clients and implemented multiple marketing services across platforms while growing client accounts.
- Executed updated marketing plans to increase branding exposure, customer traffic and sales.
- Strengthened product branding initiatives by developing communication campaigns, promotional materials, market intelligence information and databases for global market to maximize outreach.

## ALADDIN DIGITAL BANK SEO SPECIALIST

2019-2021

- Implemented SEO strategy, resulting in 45% increase to website hits.
  - Monitored social media activity and website traffic.
  - Managed social media accounts by composing content, engaging with followers in comments, monitoring activities and researching trends.
  - Executed SEO functions such as keyword research, data collection, link optimization and site auditing.
  - Provided optimization of web page titles, URLs, structured data, SEO copy editing and sitemaps.
  - Performed keyword research and competitive analysis to identify effective strategies to meet client goals.
  - Analyzed traffic and conversion trends and developed strategies to improve traffic.
  - Devised strategies to correct SEO underperformance and resultantly increase traffic and visibility.
  - Developed SEO strategy, defined goals and prioritized tests and projects.

## **EDUCATION**

Polytechnic Ibadan (HND) Electrical Electronics 2013-2017

## **PROFESSIONAL TOOLS**

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP | ADOBE PREMIER PRO | CANVA | FIGMA | HTML5 | CSS 3

#### REFERENCE

Available on request